# Ralfi Salhon

# Mobile & Front-End Software Engineer

Portfolio: https://ralfi.dev Contact: ralfisalhon@gmail.com Github://ralfisalhon LinkedIn://ralfisalhon

#### **About Me**

Passionate software engineer interested in the field from as early as 13 years old. Experienced in working with engineers who have a collective goal of releasing high quality software. Seeking to surround myself with people who like to teach and to learn from each other. I also am a;

• Classical Pianist • Swimmer • Video Editor • Game Designer • Hackathon Enthusiast • World's Fastest Smartphone Typer (2019)

#### **Education**

**Tufts University**, Medford, MA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.59/4.0

On Campus Employment, Teaching Assistant

Computation Theory: Course on the models of computation - Turing machines, pushdown automata, and finite automata
 Computer System Security: Network-based computer security course (Python, JavaScript, Linux)
 Game Design: Ground-up game design and development course (Unity, C#, Photoshop, Maya)

Fall 2018

University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong. Tufts University study abroad program with focus on music and history.

Spring 2019

#### **Skills**

Libraries and Frameworks: React.js • React Native • Node.js • Express • Firebase • AuthO • Cypress.io • RxJS • Styled-Components • Redux Languages and Tools: TypeScript • JavaScript • HTML • CSS • Python • Go • C++ • C • Heroku • MongoDB • Testflight • Git • VSCode Design Software: Illustrator • Photoshop • After Effects • Final Cut Pro • Figma • PyxelEdit

## **Work Experience**

Talos Trading, New York, NY

Jun 2020 - Present

Front-End Developer

React.js, TypeScript, React Native, Go, RxJS

Spring 2018

- Developed high-performance components, tests, and deployment tools, ensuring efficient and reliable software delivery.
- Contributed to the growth of Talos from a 10-member team to over 130 employees, actively involved in all aspects of product development.
- Created detailed monitoring panels for Talos's institutional partners, enabling effective order lifecycle management.

Web Programming: Full-stack web development course (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB)

- Served as the primary technical support contact for clients, prioritizing and executing customer requests to ensure exceptional service delivery.
- Fostered team engagement by organizing and hosting regular company game nights, promoting a positive work culture.

JumboCode, Somerville, MA Jan 2020 - May 2020

Front-End Developer

React.js, Node.js, Firebase, Heroku

- Translated design team's UX wireframes and mockups into responsive, interactive features using React, HTML/CSS and JavaScript.
- Standardized all components with a new, responsive, mobile-friendly approach and strategy.

Insider, Istanbul, Turkey

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

Mobile Development Intern

React Native, React.js, Redux, Python

- Improved the reliability of the Insider iOS and Android SDK by implementing new geolocation and push notification algorithms.
- Developed and documented "iGurme", an e-commerce app which integrates all the features of Insider's enterprise level SDK. iGurme is currently used during sales and pitch meetings to promote Insider's new SDK features for both iOS and Android devices in over a dozen countries.

Pushlogic, Hong Kong May 2018 - Sep 2018

React Native Developer (Remote)

React Native, Firebase, Figma

- Architected, developed, and documented the mobile app of a security platform that provides real-time threat protection.
- Implemented support for auto-login and token retrieval/refresh, advanced push notifications.
- Deployed and maintained "Polysentry" on the App Store and Google Play Store.

## **Personal Projects**

Most of my projects are open-sourced, I'm also always working on more: Github://ralfisalhon

TuneWise	Music centered mobile party game.	tunewise.netlify.app	Oct 2019 - Dec 2019
Jamblr	Music discovery and playlist creation platform.	apple.co/2MMTKtR	Oct 2018 - May 2019
Coverlove	Cover art maker for Spotify playlists.	apple.co/3oXbPNb	Feb 2019 - Mar 2019
<b>Red or Blue</b>	Strategy puzzle platformer game with controller support.	bit.ly/redorbluegame	Sep 2017 - Jan 2018